<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ddns | Troglobit]]></title>
  <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/categories/ddns/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-16T21:26:44+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://troglobit.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joachim Nilsson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[troglobit@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GnuTLS Support in Inadyn and Fixes to Uftpd]]></title>
    <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2014/09/13/gnutls-support-in-inadyn-and-fixes-to-uftpd/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-13T19:18:56+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2014/09/13/gnutls-support-in-inadyn-and-fixes-to-uftpd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quite a few changes lately.  I finally got around to adding support
for <a href="http://www.gnutls.org">GnuTLS</a> to <a href="/inadyn.html">Inadyn</a>,
hopefully this will get into Debian &hellip; unless the Jessie freeze
prevents that.</p>

<p>Also, thanks to a friend of mine trying out <a href="/uftpd.html">uftpd</a>
recently I discovered that libuev has been missing from the tarball
since the release of the TFTP support.  Fixed.</p>

<p>Another great piece of news is that
<a href="http://www.coverity.com/">Coverity</a> accepted uftpd as an Open Source
project, I&rsquo;ve been hard at work fixing nasty bugs uncovered by the
<a href="https://scan.coverity.com/">Coverity Scan</a>.  Great stuff! :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Releases of Uftpd and Inadyn ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2014/05/20/new-release-of-uftpd-and-inadyn-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-20T21:08:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2014/05/20/new-release-of-uftpd-and-inadyn-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last couple of weeks have both seen the birth of the fabulous
<a href="/uftpd.html">uftpd</a> and a reignited <a href="/inadyn.html">inadyn</a> project!
Yesterday v1.2 of uftpd was released and today Inadyn saw the first
working HTTPS support being released as v1.99.8!  This is likely the
last release of Inadyn before the big 2.0, which will introduce the
new .conf file format based on
<a href="http://www.nongnu.org/confuse/">libConfuse</a>.  A .conf file
feasibility study was
<a href="/blog/2014/02/23/weekend-hack-json-vs-conf/">presented earlier</a> &hellip;</p>

<p>The uftpd project is completely based on user input, currently mostly
mine.  I will add features and bug fixes when I need them, unless I
get more input.  So I welcome anyone to clone it on GitHub and hack
away.  As usual, I will accept any sane patches that adhere to the
coding style and is well written.  The same goes for Inadyn, only with
the added request that the changes are thoroughly tested first, since
I cannot maintain multiple accounts on various DDNS providers myself.</p>

<p>Patches to support flavors of UNIX other than GNU/Linux, including
GNU/Hurd, or even other operating systems are also welcome, as long as
it&rsquo;s not Windows.  I will not maintain any Windows support since I
don&rsquo;t use it myself.  If you want Windows support you will have to
take a very active co-maintainer role in the respective project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Release of the DDNS Client Inadyn]]></title>
    <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/new-release-of-the-ddns-client-inadyn/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T08:29:48+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/new-release-of-the-ddns-client-inadyn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a Dynamic DNS, DDNS, client?  Well you&rsquo;re in luck, the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alternative_terms_for_free_software" title="FLOSS">FLOSS</a> market space is flooded with dedicated clients and various
wget scripts.  So why bother with an old C implementation?  Well, this
is admittedly one of the old timers in the game and is likely packaged
for your GNU/Linux distribution of choice already.  It&rsquo;s tried and
tested with many DDNS service providers and even comes bundled in a
few embedded router distributions as well.</p>

<p>Today I&rsquo;ve released <a href="/inadyn.html">Inadyn</a> v1.99.7 as an XZ compressed
tarball.  The release announcement should be up on <a href="https://freecode.com/projects/inadyn">free(code)</a>
now.  It&rsquo;s a small incremental release containing mainly code cleanup
and a few new features that you likely won&rsquo;t notice: support for
multiple cache files and DDNS providers as separate plugins, for easy
addition of new ones as well as maintenance of existing.  This further
separates the internal logic from the provider specific parts and also
helps reduce clutter to ease maintenance.</p>

<p>This is a small incremental release building up to the long awaited
v2.0, which will include the long-awaited HTTPS support and also a new
.conf file format.  The latter is not really welcomed with open arms
by users, but is a necessary step since the current parser is heavily
affected by bit rot and must be put down.  I will attempt to make the
transition as easy as possible, but you will need to change you .conf
files.</p>

<p>Maybe a preview of the HTTPS support will make it into a release that
still has the old .conf file format, but just maybe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
