<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joachim Wiberg</title>
    <link>https://troglobit.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joachim Wiberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>UNIX&amp;trade; 4Life! &amp;#9994;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 06:47:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://troglobit.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this little blog, my name is Joachim Wiberg, formerly Nilsson. The nick troglobit is a tribute to my childhood friend Henrik Flordal, for being a good friend and inspiring me to become a hacker. It is also the first password to a Linux server (Henrik&amp;rsquo;s) I got a login to, back in 1995.&#xA;So yes, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge Linux and UNIX nerd. Ever since my first job, after graduating from MdU, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running Linux on almost all my machines, including those at work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast init for Linux systems</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/projects/finit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 06:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/projects/finit/</guid>
      <description>Finit is an alternative to SysV init and systemd, originally reverse engineered from the EeePC fastinit by Claudio Matsuoka — &amp;ldquo;gaps filled with frog DNA …&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Latest release available on GitHub&#xA;Features Runlevels, defined per service One-shot tasks, services (daemons), or SysV init start/stop scripts Runparts and /etc/rc.local support Process supervision similar to systemd Sourcing environment files Conditions for network/process/custom dependencies Pre/Post script actions Tooling to enable/disable services Optional built-in getty Optional built-in watchdog, with support for hand-over to watchdogd Built-in support for Debian/BusyBox /etc/network/interfaces, automatically calls ifup/ifdown Cgroups v2, both configuration and monitoring in initctl top Plugin support for customization Proper rescue mode with bundled sulogin for protected maintenance shell (optional) Blog Posts Some of these feature are presented below, for more, see the online documentation and the following blog posts:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HowTo play with SNMP</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/howtos/snmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 20:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/howtos/snmp/</guid>
      <description>This mini HowTo describes how to use the SNMP client tools to retrieve human readable information from devices running an SNMP daemon. In the examples below mini-snmpd is used as the daemon and as client both the command line net-snmp tool and the snmpB GUI are used.&#xA;Personally I use both Ubuntu and Debian, so the tools I use to download the clients will reflect that. See your respective UNIX distro&amp;rsquo;s help pages for how to install these client tools in your operating system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buildroot Development Checklist</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/post/2023-06-04-buildroot-development-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 17:49:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/post/2023-06-04-buildroot-development-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I always forget, here&amp;rsquo;s a reminder to myself on how to use &lt;code&gt;git format-patch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git send-email&lt;/code&gt; from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following process applies to many other mailing-list based&#xA;projects as well, with local differences in helper scripts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multicast HowTo</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/howtos/multicast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 07:52:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/howtos/multicast/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This HowTo attempts to give some insight into the basics of setting up multicast routing. Both static multicast routing, with SMCRoute, and dynamic multicast routing, with mrouted and pimd.&#xA;For some use-cases, in particular link-local multicast, it may not be possible to use multicast routing, then I recommend trying out:&#xA;Bridging networks, see bridge(8) or Linux bridge - how it works igmproxy, mcproxy, or OpenVPN in Layer-2, bridged mode Make sure to check out the FAQ for the most common problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finit custom connectivity check</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/post/2023-01-15-finit-custom-connectivity-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 18:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/post/2023-01-15-finit-custom-connectivity-check/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post shows how you can extend Finit with your own conditions.  The&#xA;example we will use is a simple Internet connectivity checker.  When it&#xA;triggers we start BusyBox ntpd which, if started with any other type of&#xA;condition (none, default route, etc.) may get stuck trying to resolve&#xA;&lt;code&gt;pool.ntp.org&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buildroot demo of FastInit (Finit)</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/post/2022-12-26-buildroot-demo-of-fastinit-finit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 21:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/post/2022-12-26-buildroot-demo-of-fastinit-finit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe there is a &lt;strong&gt;gap in the market&lt;/strong&gt; between BusyBox init and&#xA;systemd.  In particular in the embedded space.  This blog post shows how&#xA;easily it is to get up and running quickly with FastInit (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/troglobit/finit#introduction&#34;&gt;Finit&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a really bad salesman, and an even worse writer, so instead of&#xA;trying to convince you with my poor English, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a demo.  It is a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nightly.buildroot.org/#outside-br-custom&#34;&gt;Buildroot external&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;that can be used to add Finit to your own projects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For details, look here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/troglobit/br2-finit-demo&#34;&gt;https://github.com/troglobit/br2-finit-demo&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;try out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/troglobit/br2-finit-demo/releases/tag/latest&#34;&gt;latest build&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.qemu.org&#34;&gt;Qemu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://troglobit.com/images/finit-demo/bootstrap.png&#34; alt=&#34;Finit bootstrap&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remap Prev/Next on ThinkPad</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/post/2022-10-01-remap-prev/next-on-thinkpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 15:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/post/2022-10-01-remap-prev/next-on-thinkpad/</guid>
      <description>I still use my awesome little ThinkPad X200, in fact I now have more of them and even a few X201&amp;rsquo;s. They are truly the best machines I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used! :-)&#xA;One annoying thing though, when going back to these traditional ThinkPad keyboards is the prev/next keys next to the arrow keys. On modern ones they are PgUp/PgDn and I recently learned how to elegantly remap them in X. Note the difference, below, to the original at ThinkWiki.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logging to remote syslog servers</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/post/2022-09-09-logging-to-remote-syslog-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 19:36:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/post/2022-09-09-logging-to-remote-syslog-servers/</guid>
      <description>The logger(1) tool in your system, /usr/bin/logger, standardized in IEEE Std 1003.2 (&amp;ldquo;POSIX.2&amp;rdquo;), has many different implementations. For Linux users the most common one is part of the util-linux package.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve always considered this one of those weird Linux:isms. The logger tool is closely tied to the system log daemon, so in the sysklogd project we ship our own implementation of logger. Our implementation is derived from the Finit project&amp;rsquo;s logit tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Multicast Routing Daemon</title>
      <link>https://troglobit.com/projects/smcroute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 10:00:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troglobit.com/projects/smcroute/</guid>
      <description>SMCRoute is a daemon and command line tool to manipulate the multicast routing table in the UNIX kernel. Both FreeBSD and Linux kernels are supported, but it may work on other systems as well.&#xA;SMCRoute can be used as an alternative to dynamic multicast routing daemons like mrouted or pimd when (only) static multicast routes should be maintained or no proper signalling exists.&#xA;The full documentation of SMCRoute is available in the manual pages, see smcrouted(8), smcroutectl(8), and smcroute.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
