<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Troglobit</title>
    <link>/categories/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Troglobit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 19:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 8.10rc1 &amp;mdash; NetworkManager WTF?!</title>
      <link>/2008/10/27/ubuntu-8-dot-10rc1-networkmanager-wtf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 19:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>/2008/10/27/ubuntu-8-dot-10rc1-networkmanager-wtf/</guid>
      <description>I tried upgrading from Hardy Heron to Intrepid Ibex this weekend. Big mistake. If I disregard the total dpkg meltdown that I, as usually, had to resolve manually there still remains this recurring madness called Network Manager.
I&amp;rsquo;m an engineer. I have a masters degree in computer engineering. I have worked professionally with GNU/Linux since 2000 and been a die hard user of it since I left OS/2 behind in 1996.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netapplet Patchwork</title>
      <link>/2007/07/12/netapplet-patchwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 11:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>/2007/07/12/netapplet-patchwork/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;rsquo;ve finally done it &amp;mdash; achieved my ultimate goal of combining the awesome powers of the Debian /etc/network/interfaces file with guessnet, wpa_supplicant, ifplugd and now also with netapplet!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a way to just point-and-click to select a different access point, both at home and at work. To that end I have a pretty advanced interfaces file that automatically detects where I am, what I am connected with (cable/wireless) and then, like magic, sets it all up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Note</title>
      <link>/2006/07/17/quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 21:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>/2006/07/17/quick-note/</guid>
      <description>About that /etc/network/interface autoconfig thingy: it&amp;rsquo;s almost done. Works perfect &amp;hellip; at work (connected) and at home (wireless). I need to fine tune the tests, I think, to get the connected stuff to work at home too. The problem seems to be that the test to see if the machine is connected at home is that the MAC it looks for to ID the office network also is available from home, via the VPN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop Network Configuration in Debian/Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/2006/06/06/laptop-network-configuration-in-debian-slash-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 21:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>/2006/06/06/laptop-network-configuration-in-debian-slash-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I have three network cards in my laptop. Two built-in and one PCMCIA card. I&amp;rsquo;m currently investigating how I can migrate from using the slow and tedious gnome-network &amp;amp; C:o tools to the more integrated Debian/Ubuntu tools ifupdown, guessnet, ifplugd and waproamd instead. As usual Debian has a fine and clever way of handling all this with their /etc/network/interface file. To learn more about this fine management interface I&amp;rsquo;m reading the well written book The Debian System by Martin F.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>