<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on </title>
    <link>/categories/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 01:38:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Build GNU Emacs from CVS</title>
      <link>/2008/07/28/howto-build-gnu-emacs-from-cvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 01:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>/2008/07/28/howto-build-gnu-emacs-from-cvs/</guid>
      <description>Why would you want to do this? Well, considering all the neat new things that have been added lately it should be tempting for any old Emacs fan.
The Emacs Wiki has all the info you need, but here is a quick run-down of the bare necessities. Start by checking out your working copy:
cvs -z3 -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.savannah.gnu.org:/cvsroot/emacs co emacs cd emacs/ ./configure make bootstrap  Start with ./src/emacs or symlink the binary to your ~/bin/ directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Emacs Progress!</title>
      <link>/2008/07/22/more-emacs-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 23:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>/2008/07/22/more-emacs-progress/</guid>
      <description>Wow, I&amp;rsquo;m almost starting to feel like a Windows user. The latest CVS builds of GNU Emacs has a lot of new features:
 XFT Support (font anti-aliasing) Better GTK integration (desktop) A font selector!  I use the CVS version now as my daily driver in Ubuntu 8.10. It&amp;rsquo;s really useful, and I love the improved support for debugging programs inside Emacs!
I think it is quite impressive how far this little editor has come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Emacs</title>
      <link>/2008/02/24/enterprise-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 10:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>/2008/02/24/enterprise-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many years ago I discovered the beauty in a beast called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;.  I
am actually a frequent user of both Emacs and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;, but I firmly
belive in the notion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/the-pragmatic-programmer/extracts/tips&#34;&gt;learning one editor well&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The editor should be an extension of your hand; make sure your editor
is configurable, extensible, and programmable.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pragmaticprogrammer.com/the-pragmatic-programmer/extracts/tips&#34;&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the many jobs I have had, colleagues often glanced over my shoulder
and said; &amp;ldquo;Oh, Emacs&amp;nbsp;&amp;hellip; Yeah I used that ages ago when I was
working on UNIX&amp;nbsp;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;, often they remember it fondly, sometimes for
all the quirky keyboard shortcuts.  Very few know that it is still being
actively developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emacs can be quite counter intuitive and sometimes even an outright pain
to use.  I find it a shame that still today, after (literally) decades
there are no sane defaults.  Once, when I was still forced to use
Windows, I saw a setup wizard in &lt;a href=&#34;http://ntemacs.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Win32-Emacs&lt;/a&gt; that resembled what I
would like to have — a sort of use cases possible to chose from.  It may
have been some extension that was maintained in some non-official
version, because now when I look for it I cannot find it.  But why not
have a setup wizard in the upstream distribution of Emacs as well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this is my gripe, the pieces of Emacs that are still unfriendly to
users, and mostly new users, coming from Windows or MAC.  I will use
this blog to present ideas and small things I have done to make Emacs
more user friendly.  I call this &lt;em&gt;Enterprise Emacs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>