<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Troglobit</title>
    <link>http://troglobit.com/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Troglobit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://troglobit.com/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads vs Events</title>
      <link>http://troglobit.com/2013/08/06/event-handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>http://troglobit.com/2013/08/06/event-handling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a rant about something I recently found to be a long standing
battle line in the world of programming,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cgi.di.uoa.gr/~mema/courses/mde518/papers/lauer78.pdf&#34;&gt;Lau78&lt;/a&gt;.
The event vs thread based approach to programming.  As rants go I do
not aspire to deliver a clear or logical message, what so ever.  It&amp;rsquo;s
basically just something I need to get off my chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not until 2007 I first learned about the event based approach
to programming and event libraries like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://libevent.org/&#34;&gt;libevent&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://software.schmorp.de/pkg/libev.html&#34;&gt;libev&lt;/a&gt;.  Up until that
point the silver bullet everyone was using was &amp;hellip; Threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Open Source Releases</title>
      <link>http://troglobit.com/2013/07/12/new-open-source-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>http://troglobit.com/2013/07/12/new-open-source-releases/</guid>
      <description>Vacation time means catching up on my Open Source projects! :)
Currently I&amp;rsquo;m shaping up the home pages and this blog to improve the easy access and overview of all the packages I maintain. The following packages have new releases, or can expect new releases soon:
 Minix Editline v1.14.1 SMCRoute v1.99.1 &amp;ndash; There&amp;rsquo;s even a v2.0.0 being planned, with the core of SMCRoute available as a library mrouted minor cleanup an sync with OpenBSD pimd cleanups and bug fixes, needs testing inadyn is in dire need of a release, but needs more testing and fixes  As usual, see my GitHub for the latest commits if you want to try anything out, file an issue report, or if you want to contribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finit v1.8</title>
      <link>http://troglobit.com/2013/06/08/finit-v1-dot-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>http://troglobit.com/2013/06/08/finit-v1-dot-8/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming, but here it finally is, Finit v1.8! The goodies we&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for are:
 Runlevels Multiple TTYs One-shot tasks  Let&amp;rsquo;s start off with tasks. Tasks are one-shot commands, with a syntax like service directives, but are not monitored and respawned like services. Tasks are started in parallel, just like services. For some cases, like the system bootstrap phase, some tasks may need to be executed in sequence, and for that purpose there also exists a run command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editline First Post</title>
      <link>http://troglobit.com/2009/06/14/editline-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 20:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>troglobit@gmail.com (Joachim Nilsson)</author>
      <guid>http://troglobit.com/2009/06/14/editline-first-post/</guid>
      <description>For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been maintaining a port of the Minix editline library libedit. Mainly for my own purposes, or rather on behalf of Westermo WeOS, where it is used in the CLI. This library is the same as the Debian editline package, even though the origin of that package is somewhat unclear to me.
Today I decided to adjust the package name and bump the version number to indicate that my port is the same, and now slightly more advanced, than the Debian version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>