<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Networking | Troglobit]]></title>
  <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/categories/networking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-08T02:42:03+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://troglobit.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joachim Nilsson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[troglobit@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 8.10rc1 &mdash; NetworkManager WTF?!]]></title>
    <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2008/10/27/ubuntu-8-dot-10rc1-networkmanager-wtf/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-27T18:50:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2008/10/27/ubuntu-8-dot-10rc1-networkmanager-wtf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I tried upgrading from Hardy Heron to Intrepid Ibex this weekend.  Big
mistake.  If I disregard the total dpkg meltdown that I, as usually, had
to resolve manually there still remains this recurring madness called
Network Manager.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m an engineer.  I have a masters degree in computer engineering.  I
have worked professionally with GNU/Linux since 2000 and been a die hard
user of it since I left OS/2 behind in 1996.  But come on!  Why does it
take a software engineer to perform a simple upgrade?  Even worse, why
do I have to be a network engineering specialist to figure out why
simple wired ethernet doesn&rsquo;t work out of the box?</p>

<p>Network Manager fails completely to:</p>

<ol>
<li>Select wired network over an open Telia hotspot</li>
<li>Distinguish between my primary and secondary wired interfaces</li>
<li>Completely loses my <code>/etc/resolv.conf</code> all the time</li>
</ol>


<p>Sorry, but that is completely inexcusable!  <a href="http://www.gnome.org/projects/NetworkManager/">Network Manager</a>, you
suck!  &ldquo;Pain-Free Networking&rdquo;, my ass! :-P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netapplet Patchwork]]></title>
    <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2007/07/12/netapplet-patchwork/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-12T11:37:38+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2007/07/12/netapplet-patchwork</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think I&rsquo;ve finally done it &mdash; achieved my ultimate goal of
combining the awesome powers of the Debian <code>/etc/network/interfaces</code>
file with <code>guessnet</code>, <code>wpa_supplicant</code>, <code>ifplugd</code> and now also with
netapplet!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been looking for a way to just point-and-click to select a
different access point, both at home and at work.  To that end I have a
pretty advanced interfaces file that automatically detects where I am,
what I am connected with (cable/wireless) and then, like magic, sets it
all up.</p>

<p>Several times now I have tried, really hard, to get used to and live my
life with <a href="http://www.gnome.org/projects/NetworkManager/">Network Manager</a>, but it&rsquo;s just plain impossible.  It
still doesn&rsquo;t integrate well with Debian ifupdown et consortes and until
now I&rsquo;ve been using <code>ifup</code> to select different wireless mappings:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo ifdown eth2; sudo ifup eth2=WLAN
Password: ***********
[Use crappy work AP to access VPN tunnel]
$ sudo ifdown eth2; sudo ifup eth2=NETLET
Password: ***********
[Use family WRT54GL access point]
</code></pre>

<p>For the last couple of days I&rsquo;ve been looking into getting the old
(obsoleted?) Netapplet from Novell.  Since I&rsquo;m a Ubuntu user I&rsquo;m using
the Debian patched-up version by <a href="http://mjg59.livejournal.com/">Matthew Garrett</a> (thanks!).  I
remember using it a couple of years back, at that time I think it worked
but now it didn&rsquo;t &mdash; not well at least.  I found several bugs and
quirks that I have now fixed and published in my own &ldquo;repository&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I have published everything as a Bazaar branch, one changeset per patch
(small patches), at <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20090528101921/http://vmlinux.org/jocke/bzr/netapplet-1.0.8/">http://vmlinux.org/jocke/bzr/netapplet-1.0.8</a>,
which can be viewed <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20090528101921/http://vmlinux.org/jocke/bzr/">here</a> using bzrweb.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick Note]]></title>
    <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2006/07/17/quick-note/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-17T21:10:45+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2006/07/17/quick-note</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About that <code>/etc/network/interface</code> autoconfig thingy: it&rsquo;s almost done.
Works perfect &hellip; at work (connected) and at home (wireless).  I need to
fine tune the tests, I think, to get the connected stuff to work at home
too.  The problem seems to be that the test to see if the machine is
connected at home is that the MAC it looks for to ID the office network
also is available from home, via the VPN.  I&rsquo;ll get back on the subject
as soon as I&rsquo;ve done some more tests.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laptop Network Configuration in Debian/Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2006/06/06/laptop-network-configuration-in-debian-slash-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-06T21:10:24+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://troglobit.github.io/blog/2006/06/06/laptop-network-configuration-in-debian-slash-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have three network cards in my laptop.  Two built-in and one PCMCIA
card.  I&rsquo;m currently investigating how I can migrate from using the slow
and tedious gnome-network &amp; C:o tools to the more integrated
Debian/Ubuntu tools <code>ifupdown</code>, <code>guessnet</code>, <code>ifplugd</code> and <code>waproamd</code>
instead.  As usual Debian has a fine and clever way of handling all this
with their <code>/etc/network/interface</code> file.  To learn more about this
<a href="http://www.debian.org/doc/manuals/reference/ch-gateway.en.html">fine management interface</a> I&rsquo;m reading the well written book
<a href="http://debiansystem.info/">The Debian System</a> by <a href="http://madduck.net/blog/">Martin F. Krafft</a>.  I highly recommend it
to others wanting to learn the essentials of their Debian (based)
system.</p>

<p>What I wanted to do is quite simple actually: the built-in wired
interface, named <code>eth0</code>, should on link-up default to a specific IP
address if ARP reveals a certain MAC on the network.  If plugged in to
an unknown net <code>eth0</code> should go up with DHCP.  If <code>eth0</code> is not up then
the built-in wlan card, <code>eth1</code>, should be tried with two different
ESSID&rsquo;s, work and home, in that order.  If none of the ESSID&rsquo;s could be
found any open WiFi access point should be the tried with DHCP.  The
last interface, <code>eth2</code>, is the PCMCIA card and is only used for the lab
net and always have the same IP address if plugged in completely
ignoring link status.</p>

<p>When I&rsquo;ve implemented the above I&rsquo;ll post the result here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
