<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>howto on Joachim Wiberg</title>
    <link>/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in howto on Joachim Wiberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>UNIX&amp;trade; 4Life! &amp;#9994;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 16:56:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Own Operating System</title>
      <link>/post/2022-04-17-your-own-operating-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 16:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-04-17-your-own-operating-system/</guid>
      <description>This post shows how you can create your own operating system based on Buildroot. Add your own packages, patches, and your very own flavor to the experience.
 My own take on this is myLinux, which started out as a TroglOS, and before that as miniroot, by Henrik Nordström. Please feel free to dig around myLinux for more inspiration and tips on how to solve common use-cases.
 The manual, section 9, describes the basic process of setting up a our customizations as a BR2_EXTERNAL tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finit in Linux Containers (LXC)</title>
      <link>/post/2022-02-13-finit-in-linux-containers-lxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 17:55:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-02-13-finit-in-linux-containers-lxc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a mini-HowTo on running Finit in an LXC system container.  We
will be using a variant (external) of Buildroot, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/westermo/netbox&#34;&gt;NetBox&lt;/a&gt; to
create a squashfs (read-only) image for the root filesystem.  Then we
will give the container a single writable directory from which it then
uses bind mount to emulate a full-blown system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is expected you have LXC installed and all the relevant build tools
needed to create the image.  How to set that up is not covered by this
tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail and git send-email</title>
      <link>/post/2022-01-24-gmail-and-git-send-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 19:37:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-01-24-gmail-and-git-send-email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to my previous Buildroot mailing-list post about the
&lt;code&gt;git format-patch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git send-email&lt;/code&gt; commands, this post covers how
to set up the latter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>